# Carlos R. Castillo

Software Engineer 575-418-7906 xxp7cl@m.hackerx.org Seattle, WA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlosrcastillo/ Personal Portfolio: https://carloscastillo.us/

Experienced software engineer with solid expertise in several spaces of enterprise software development lifecycle. I'm inherently a strategic thinker and enjoy solving difficult problems. But also, not afraid to ask for help on blockers. A diverse technical background drives my aggressive analytical thinking and excellent communication skills. As an innovator, I want to use my experience in software, team collaboration, and design to bring value to the company.

#### **TOOLS**

C# JavaScript Java JSON API Git SQL HTML/CSS Azure

.Net Framework Agile DevOps Storage CI/CD Testing

### **PROJECTS**

### **Microsoft Edge Sites**

September 2022

- Microsoft websites for US and world.
  - https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge
  - https://www.microsoft.com/en
    -us/edge/business
- Build, collaborate, maintain, and update
  12+ sites in 37 languages.
- .Net Framework, C#, JS, JSON, CSS, Figma, and Azure: App Service, VM, Blobs, App Insights, Key Vaults, CDN.

#### Hackathon

February 2020

- Hosted by Seattle Makers: <u>https://hacksinahurry.com</u>
- Build a "voting game" to elect new president of earth. Teams of 4.
- JS, React, HTML, CSS, 3-D printing, and imagination.

#### **HealthCare API**

January 2021

- Capstone Project.
- Build REST API for HealthCare
- Structured SQL DB with CRUD operations.
- Spring Boot & JPA, MySQL Workbench, Swagger, Eclipse.
- Using Object-Oriented Programming concepts.
- Private GitHub repository.

#### InstaHub

March 2019

- Chat messaging application using SignalR preview mode: <a href="https://dev.azure.com/CF-DNet-FinalTeam/git/instaHub">https://dev.azure.com/CF-DNet-FinalTeam/git/instaHub</a>
- ASP.Net Core, C#, Razor Pages, LINQ, AuthO by Okta, Azure SQL, xUnit Testing.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **HCL Tech | Software Developer**

October 2020 – February 2023

My journey at HCL Tech started with the Software Development team where I was onboarded as a Software Developer. After an initial training where I with a team of 4 built an API for HealthCare project, I joined the Microsoft Engineering and R&D Services(ERS). I was put on a small team to bring Microsoft 365 Life Hacks articles <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/enus/microsoft-365-life-hacks">https://www.microsoft.com/enus/microsoft-365-life-hacks</a> up to date with new content and create some new articles as well. They were hosted on WordPress using PHP.

I then transitioned into Microsoft Edge Product for consumer and business. Working with a team from Redmond WA, Canada, and India we successfully modified current sites and build some new sites. Coding the project was mostly in C# with some LINQ, JavaScript, CSS, and JSON. I also used Azure tools on the project often. This included services like App Services, Application Insights for monitoring, blob storage, VM for testing legacy systems using Internet Explorer 11, CDN, Redis Caches, and Key Vault. I was responsible for also running CI/CD pipelines for testing and staging sites. I also held meetings with stakeholders who were responsible for wireframe designs, copyright images, and updating Figma to follow the clients request and expectations. My time at HCL Tech allowed me to get my certification from Microsoft which include AZ-900 Certification, SC-900 Certification, and DP-900 Certification.

Agile Compliance AZ DevOps Storage CI/CD MVC Testing

## People Tech Group Inc. | Jr. Programmer Analyst

February 2020 – March2020

At People Tech Group, I started as a Jr Programmer for Azure Data Lakes project. I was being trained on the current project involving big data sets focusing mostly on AZ Data Lake Storage using C# and SQL Databases. As great of an opportunity this was, after a month in the role, Covid-19 hit, and the company decided to close in-person offices.

### Azure Data Lake SQL AZ DevOps

### **IEH Laboratories & Consulting Group | Scientist**

September 2015 – September 2018

After University, I began my career originally as a Chemist. At work, I would work with macros that made data entry and analysis easier. Then during my free time, I began to study coding and started to fall in love with software development. Eventually, my career change and journey lead me to become a software engineer.

### **EDUCATION**

**Code Fellows** 

Advanced Software Development

**New Mexico Institute of Mining & Technology** 

Bachelor of Science

Seattle, WA

March 2019

Socorro, NM

May 2008